Guide to the Steven Meretzky papers relating to computer game design and interactive fiction history, 1978-2009 M1730
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Steven Meretzky Papers
Circa 1978-2009
M1730
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
43.5 Linear feet (54 boxes, 1 flat box, 6 map folders, 1 map tube)
The papers include design and game development documents, correspondence, paper files, electronic games, magazines, data disks, original game package artwork, PR and marketing materials, and miscellaneous electronic game industry memorabilia.
Meretzky, Steve
Boffo Games, Inc.
Related resource: Boffo Games collection, 1993-1996. Stanford University Libraries.
Biographical Note
Steven Meretzky was born on May 1, 1957 in Yonkers, NY. He attended MIT in 1975 in pursuit of an architecture career, and was majoring in construction management when he changed his career goals to focus on computer game development. His roommate at the time, Mike Dornbrook, was working as the first and only game tester for Infocom, a computer game publisher specializing in text adventures (aka “interactive fiction”) titles. Interactive fiction games are controlled by the player through a text-based parser, which interprets simple instructions that the player types into the computer, such as “get lamp.” Dornbrook was play testing the title Zork I in their living room on an Apple II computer, recording any programming bugs, and Meretzky assisted (unpaid) because of his interest in the game. Dornbrook eventually left to attend business school, leaving Infocom in need of a new game tester. In 1981, Marc Blank, Infocom’s VP of Development, hired Meretzky to fill the vacated position. Meretzky worked as a game tester for one year and then was offered the opportunity to develop his first game, Planetfall, which was released in 1983.
He went on to develop dozens of classic Infocom titles during the 1980s, including A Mind Forever Voyaging, Sorcerer, and Zork Zero, eventually gaining entry into the Science Fiction Writers of America (one of only two game writers admitted, the other being Dave Lebling, another Infocom employee). Infocom was a leading creator of interactive fiction computer games during the 1980s, gaining a reputation for high quality packaging design, programming, and writing. In 1984 Meretzky had his most famous collaboration with Douglas Adams, on the computer game version of The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy. He has been involved in almost every aspect of game development, from writing to design to quality assurance and product design.
Sources:
Montfort, Nick. Twisty Little Passages: An Approach to Interactive Fiction. Cambridge: MIT Press, 2005
http://www.adventureclassicgaming.com/index.php/site/interviews/169/
http://www.linkedin.com/pub/steven-meretzky/4/16/a95
http://www.getlamp.com/cast/20060718meretzky/index.html
http://www.getlamp.com/cast/20060718meretzky/FILES/meretzky_eng.html
Scope and Contents
The papers include design and game development documents, correspondence, paper files, electronic games, magazines, data disks, original game package artwork, PR and marketing materials, and miscellaneous electronic game industry memorabilia.
This collection is arranged into 9 series.
Series 1. Developed Games: This series contains computer discs and software packaging materials that are related to games developed by companies where Steven Meretzky worked. These include titles by Infocom, Inc. and Boffo Games, Inc. The computer discs are formatted for use on a variety of computing platforms, such as the Apple II, Atari 810, Macintosh, and IBM. There is also one arcade board, for the game Big Rig.
Series 2. Personal Games: This series contains a single game, Return to Zork, which was published by Activision.
Series 3. Design Notebooks: These design notebooks are arranged into 36 subseries, arranged alphabetically by game title. They include textual materials, technical specifications, artwork, scripts, financial data, and other documents generated during the game design process.
Series 4. Paper Files: This series is arranged into 16 subseries. Papers include artwork (character sketches, box cover art, maps, and environnment concepts), business documents (corporate logos, web pages, marketing materials, letterheads, human resources materials, and memos), technical documents (ZIL engine, R-Mode Editor), correspondence, newsletters, books, drafts of novels, playthrough notes, hintbooks, posters, and conference materials.
Series 5. Born-digital Materials: This series consists of backups on computer discs, including saved games from Simcity Mac 1.1 1989, audio from Boffo Games ( Hodj 'n' Podj, The Space Bar, etc.), different versions of Infocom games, and assorted game design documents. Note: This Series is CLOSED UNTIL PROCESSED.
Series 6. Periodicals: The Periodicals series contains three subseries. Subseries 1 contains issues from the Journal of Computer Game Design published between June 1987-August 1996. Subseries 2 contains issues from Questbusters: The Adventurer's Journal published between August 1991 and May 1996. Subseries 3 contains issues from the Compuer Game Developers Association Report published between 1994 and 1998.
Series 7. Realia/Ephemera: This series contains realia/ephemera related to game publisher Infocom, Inc.
Series 8. Magnetic Tape Media: This series contains magnetic tape media including audio and videotapes from the Game Developer's Conference, a videotape of the demos for the game The Space Bar, and audio cassette tapes containing audio from the games Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2, Hodj 'n' Podj, Reverse Alien, and The Space Bar.
Series 9. Photographic Scans of Selected Documents: Hard drives were given to Stanford University by Jason Scott, who scanned materials in the Steven Meretzky papers (M1730) before they were donated to the Stanford University Libraries. Jason described the materials that Meretzky provided to him as a "collection of influential writings and behind the scenes artifacts that a serious student of games and self-proposed archive of gaming materials would have to acknowledge as a world-class library." (Source: Jason Scott's weblog, (http://ascii.textfiles.com/archives/1357) The scanned items provide background on both business practice and game development at Infocom, Activision, and other companies for which Steve Meretzky worked during his illustrious career as a game designer.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Steven Meretzky, 2009. Accession 2009-304. Gift of Steven Meretzky, 2013. Accession 2013-216.
Access to Collection
Open for research, except that born-digital materials in Series 9. are CLOSED UNTIL PROCESSED. Physical boxes can be paged for use through Searchworks. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. Scans of selected documents from Series 9 are available through the media cart (dedicated offline computers) inside the Green Library reading room.
Activision, Inc.; Adams, Douglas; Blank, Marc; Boffo Games, Inc.; Infocom, Inc.; Lebling, Dave; Computer games--Design.; Computer games--History.; Computer games--Programming.
- Series 1: Developed Games
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains computer discs and software packaging materials that are related to games developed by companies where Steven Meretzky worked. These include titles by Infocom, Inc. and Boffo Games, Inc. The computer discs are formatted for use on a variety of computing platforms, such as the Apple II, Atari 810, Macintosh, and IBM. There is also one arcade board, for the game Big Rig.
  - Leather Goddesses of Phobos, Macintosh, 1988 (Box 42)
  - Zork I, Macintosh, 1988 (Box 42)
  - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy, Macintosh (Box 42)
  - Planetfall, Macintosh (Box 42)
  - Sorcerer (Box Only), 1984 (Box 42)
  - Leather Goddesses of Phobos, Apple II (Box 42)
  - Sorcerer, Atari 810 (Box 42)
  - Planetfall, DEC Rainbow (Box 42)
  - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy, Atari 810 or 1050 disk (Box 42)
  - Planetfall (Box Only) (Box 42)
  - A Mind Forever Voyaging, Apple II (Box 42)
  - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Box Only) (Box 42)
  - Planetfall (Box Only) (Box 42)
  - Hodj 'n' Podj, Windows 3.1 (Box 42)
  - Hodj 'n' Podj, Macintosh (Box 43)
  - Superhero League of Hoboken, MS-DOS 5.0, 1994 (Box 43)
  - Spellcasting Party Pak, MS-DOS (Box 43)
  - Spellcasting 301 Spring Break, MS-DOS (Box 43)
  - Space Bar, The, Windows 95, Macintosh PPC 6100 and greater (Box 43)
  - Spellcasting 101 Sorcerer's Get All the Girls, IBM PC/XT/AT/PS1/PS2 (Box 43)
  - Spellcasting 201 The Sorcerer's Appliance, IBM, Tandy, MS-DOS (Box 43)
  - Rex Nebular and the Cosmic Gender Bender, IBM PC (Box 43)
  - Four-in-one Infocom Sampler - Zork I, Witness, Infidel, Witness, Planetfall, Macintosh (Box 43)
  - Wishbringer, Macintosh, 1988 (Box 42)
  - Lane Mastodon vs. the Blubbermen (Box Only), 1988 (Box 42)
  - Big Rig (Arcade Board) (Box 48)
- Series 2: Personal Games
  This series contains a single game, Return to Zork, which was published by Activision.
  - Return To Zork (Box 55)
- Series 3: Design Notebooks
  These design notebooks are arranged into 36 subseries, arranged alphabetically by game title. They include textual materials, technical specifications, artwork, scripts, financial data, and other documents generated during the game design process.
  - Subseries 1: Big Rig
    - Big Rig - Errata (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Big Rig - Scenario (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
    - Big Rig - Technical (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Big Rig - Art (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 2: Earth Girls Are Easy
    - Earth Girls Are Easy - Movie Script (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Earth Girls Are Easy - Scenario (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Earth Girls Are Easy - Financials (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 3: Foundation Trader
    - Foundation Trader - Scenario (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Foundation Trader - Netrek Unleashed (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Foundation Trader - Tour de Sol (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Foundation Trader - Shockwave (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Foundation Trader - Design Doc (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4: Germ Warfare
    - Germ Warfare - Background (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Germ Warfare - Art (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Germ Warfare - Legal / Financial (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Germ Warfare - Design (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Germ Warfare - Technical (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Germ Warfare - Graphics (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Germ Warfare - Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 5: Hercules Mt. Olympus
    - Hercules Mt. Olympus - Concept Document (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Hercules Movie Sketches (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Hercules Movie Script (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Hercules Mt. Olympus - Information Packet (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Hercules Mt. Olympus - Background (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Hercules Mt. Olympus - Concept Docs (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Hercules Mt. Olympus - Environs and Chars (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Hercules Mt. Olympus - Adventure Stuff (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Hercules Mt. Olympus - Business (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 6: Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy
    - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Scenario) - Articles and Reviews (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Scenario) - Errata (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Scenario) - Scenario (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Scenario) - Marketing and PR (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Scenario) - Manual and Browsies (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Scenario) - Commands and Playthrough (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Scenario) - Hintbook Stuff (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Scenario) - Compilations (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 7: Hodj 'n' Podj
    - Hodj 'n' Podj Mini-Game Design - Mini-Games (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj Mini-Game Design - Misc. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj Mini-Game Design - Riddles (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj Mini-Game Design - TH GESNG GAM (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj Mini-Game Design - Cryptograms (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj Mini-Game Design - Word Search (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Intro Movie (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Meta-Game (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Memos (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Scheduling (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Financial (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Technical (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Art (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Music / Sound (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Packaging (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Marketing (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Reviews (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Mac Conversion (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Testing (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj All but Mini-Games - Geography (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj - All but Mini-Games - Errata (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj - All but Mini-Games - Virgin Datasheet (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj - All but Mini-Games - Design (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj - Packaging (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Hodj 'n' Podj - All but Mini-Games - HAPI.MPP (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 8: Infocomix
    - Infocomix: Lane Mastodon #1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Infocomix: Zork (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Infocomix: Pit of 1000 Screams (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Infocomix: Planetfall (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Infocomix: General (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 9: Kitt 'n' Kaboodul
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Design (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Geography (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Errata (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Mini Games (Box 22)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Word Search (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Anagrams (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Progressions (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Trivia (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Word Equations (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Art (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Audio (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Kitt 'n' Kaboodul - Legal / Financial (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 10: Leather Goddesses of Phobos
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Word List (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Compilations (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Outside Testing (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Hint Booklet (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Articles and Reviews (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Public Relations (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Manual (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Scenario (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos (Scenario) - Packaging (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 11: Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2 - Articles (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2 - Testing (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2 - Artwork (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2 - Technical (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2 - Legal (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2 - Chronologies (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2 - Dialogs (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2 - Scenario (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 12: Mind Forever Voyaging, A
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Compilations (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Scenario (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Testing (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Manual / Browsies (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Packaging (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Articles / Reviews (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Marketing / Public Relations (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Hintbook (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Mind Forever Voyaging, A - Decoder Prototypes (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 13: Minute Mysteries
    - Minute Mysteries - Scenario (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Minute Mysteries - Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Subseries 14: Money Game
    - Money Game - Early Notes (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Money Game - Art Direction (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Money Game - Geography (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Money Game - Overview (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Money Game - Gameplay Script (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Money Game - Events (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Money Game - Objects (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Money Game - AdZaps / Z-Buddies (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Money Game - Memos and Mail (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Money Game - Legal / Financial (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Money Game - Junior Net Backups (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 15: Planetfall
    - Planetfall (Scenario) - Misc. GR Stuff (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Planetfall (Scenario) - Errata, Packaging, Posters (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Planetfall (Scenario) - Compilations (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Planetfall (Scenario) - Scenario (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Planetfall (Scenario) - Manual, Diary, Hintbook (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Planetfall (Scenario) - Reviews, Articles (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Planetfall (Scenario) - Outside Testing (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Planetfall Cover Mock Up (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 16: Planetfall 3
    - Planetfall 3 - Background (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Planetfall 3 - Story (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Planetfall 3 - Geography (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Planetfall 3 - Characters (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Planetfall 3 - Puzzles (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Planetfall 3 - Scenes (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Planetfall 3 - Objects (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Planetfall 3 - Dialogs (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Planetfall 3 - PR (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Planetfall 3 - Legal / Financial (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Planetfall 3 - Art and Music (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 17: Restaurant at the End of the Universe
    - Restaurant at the End of the Universe (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 18: Reverse Alien
    - Reverse Alien - Scenario (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Reverse Alien - Geography (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Reverse Alien - Puzzles (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Reverse Alien - Character / Dialogs (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Reverse Alien - Objects (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Reverse Alien - Interface (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Reverse Alien - Phase I (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Reverse Alien - Phase II (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Reverse Alien - Legal / Financial (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Reverse Alien - Technical (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Reverse Alien - Art (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Reverse Alien - Sound (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 19: Scumbags
    - Scumbags - Errata (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Scumbags - Background (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Scumbags - Design (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Scumbags - Financial (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Scumbags - Art (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 20: SimElection
    - SimElection - Design (2 folders) (Box 20, Folders 1-2)
    - SimElection - Issues (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - SimElection - Candidate Data (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - SimElection - State Data (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - SimElection - Year by Year Data (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - SimElection - Art and Video (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - SimElection - Technical (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - SimElection - Memos, Agendas, Etc. (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - SimElection - Legal / Financial (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - SimElection - Errata (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - SimElection - Scheduling (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
  - Subseries 21: Smartacus
    - Smartacus - Feedback (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Smartacus - Level Design (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Smartacus - Sales Data (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Smartacus - Art (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Smartacus - Planning and Design (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Smartacus - Design (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Smartacus - Errata (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 22: Sorceror
    - Sorcerer - Errata and Infotaters (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Sorcerer - Reviews, Articles, Etc. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Sorcerer - Scenario (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Sorcerer - Compilations (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Sorcerer - Manual, Codes, Hintbook (2 folders) (Box 12, Folders 10-11)
    - Sorcerer - Misc. GR Stuff and Enchanter II (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Sorcerer - Outside Testing (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 23: Space Bar, The
    - Space Bar, The - Credits (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Space Bar, The - Manual (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Space Bar, The - Testing (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Space Bar, The - Articles (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Space Bar, The - PR (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Space Bar, The - Misc. Marketing (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Space Bar, The - Web (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Space Bar, The - Ads (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Space Bar, The - Creative Blueprint (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Space Bar, The - Focus Groups (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Space Bar, The - Demos (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Space Bar, The - Packaging (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Space Bar, The - Design Milestone 1, June 9, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Space Bar, The - Design Milestone 2, June 29, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Space Bar, The - Design Milestone 3, September 6, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Space Bar, The - Archive (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Space Bar, The - DUB Summary (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Art Specs (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Art Direction (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - DUB Memos (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Imagination Works Memos (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Internal Memos (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Misc. (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - "The Bible" (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - General Database (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Thirsty Tent (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Auditon (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Kur' Pupu (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Neblitz / Saliv (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Vedj (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Vildroid (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Space Bar, The - Art - Zzazzel (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Space Bar, The - Creative - Technical (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Space Bar, The - Creative - Interface Art (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Space Bar, The - Creative - Audio (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Space Bar, The - Creative - Music (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Space Bar, The - Creative - Random Crap (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Space Bar, The - Creative - Schedules (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Space Bar, The - Creative - Legal / Financial (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Space Bar, The - Design - Meta Game (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Space Bar, The - Meta Game - Bok's Note (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Space Bar, The - Meta Game - Storyline (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Space Bar, The - Meta Game - Meta Puzzles (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Space Bar, The - Meta Game - Gambling (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Space Bar, The - Meta Game - Drinks (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Space Bar, The - Meta Game - Entry Vestibule (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Space Bar, The - Meta Game - Residue Printing /Log (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Space Bar, The - Meta Game - Misc. Metagame (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Space Bar, The - Design - Auditon (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Space Bar, The - Design - Neblitz / Salivraster (Box 28, Folder 18)